- Previously on Gotham...
- I set a bomb.
- Thousands of people could die.
- Yes.
But paying that price will be better
than releasing what's down there.
Are you ready to play?!
Wayne Enterprises runs Indian Hill,
but who runs Wayne Enterprises?
There's a secret council in Gotham.
It's them that wanted me dead.
We're so close to the ultimate truth.
Strange, you did a very bad thing to me.
And now, you're going to...
Impossible.
Nothing is impossible.
Thank you.
Bruce, I might not see you for a while.
- Where are you going?
- I have to find Lee.
Hello?
We're closed.
If you leave now,
I won't call the cops.
Hey.
Any chance you want to come quietly?
Ow.
- sync and corrections by madhatters -
- www.addic7ed.com -
At 8:15 this evening,
an individual robbed a pharmacy
and attacked its owner.
While we don't have an I.D. as yet,
we believe this individual is
another escapee from Indian Hill.
Are these monsters dangerous?
Captain Barnes! Captain Barnes!
Valerie Vale, Gotham Gazette.
Why can't we see the escapee?
Because crews are still
picking up the pieces.
This isn't the first time
that a bounty hunter has
apprehended an escapee.
Is the GCPD incapable
of handling this threat themselves?
Whoa, only a handful of these
escapees have been brought in
by bounty hunters.
The vast majority were
apprehended by GCPD.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
I take issue with the word "threat."
These escapees are themselves
victims of Hugo Strange.
Now, if any ordinary
hard-working citizen
wants to help get these
poor souls off the street
so that they may receive
proper treatment,
well, these citizens should be lauded
and rewarded financially.
Mr. James, before they
were taken to Indian Hill,
these "poor souls" were all
criminally insane inmates
at Arkham Asylum, were they not?
Next question.
Hear that? You should be lauded.
I'll settle for the cash.
How many escapees you brought in now?
- Hmm? Six?
- Five grand a pop?
That's not too bad.
What happens when there aren't any more?
I don't think Gotham's running
out of monsters anytime soon.
I really can't get
you to come back, huh?
Look, whatever happened
when you went to see Lee,
and you know I don't like to pry...
Sure you don't.
That's because you
won't tell me anything.
The whole point is man's
not supposed to be alone.
- You have a family here.
- Can't do it, Harv.
But you got no problem
chasing down Strange's freaks?
Yeah, it pays the rent.
You are a cop in everything but name.
Yeah, except I don't
have to listen to Barnes.
I get to go home when I
want, get drunk when I want.
And at the end of the day, I sleep.
'Cause saving Gotham's
not my job anymore.
Jim, I love you like a brother,
but you've got to stop blaming the job
for what happened between you and Lee.
And do you really
think I don't get drunk when I want?
Detective Bullock?
I looked into the drug
the escapee was after.
It's a powerful immune suppressant.
Gordon.
See, look at Lucius here.
Our new resident expert
on all things scientific.
He said sayonara to
the Wayne Enterprises
robots, hmm, and he loves it here.
Wayne Enterprises revealed
itself as morally corrupt.
Here, despite the primitive facilities,
casual violence, fascistic
meathead culture...
Lucius?
I love it.
Anyway,
that drug is only sold at
three pharmacies in the city,
and the other two pharmacies were
both robbed in the last month.
The question is
why are Indian Hill escapees
now robbing pharmacies?
Good question.
So, what do you say just
like the old days you
and me run it together... Huh, partner?
You get a hard lead on an escapee
and the price is right,
I'll bring him in.
Thanks for the drink.
Lucius.
"Fascistic meathead culture"?
I mean, you couldn't try to be
just a little bit more positive?
- I was very positive.
- Uh-huh.
Why is Hugo Strange the only
one that's been arrested?
- The situation...
- And what about the rumors
that Indian Hill is a
Wayne Enterprises facility?
And how many more of these
escapees are at large?
- Are we talking 20? 30?
- Excuse me, excuse me...
Just give me a blink if I'm close.
The situation is firmly in hand.
Liar!
Oh, no.
My name is Oswald Cobblepot.
We know who you are, Penguin.
What do you want?
What do I want?
I want you to tell the truth
to the people of Gotham.
They would have us believe
that there is no danger.
But I was there the night
those creatures broke
out of Indian Hill.
I saw them.
And I saw who's leading them.
Are saying the escapees are organized?
Hello! That is what I am saying.
There is absolutely
nothing to support that.
I told the police who to look for.
I begged them time and again.
And they have done
nothing.
And so I am here
to speak directly to the good people
of Gotham.
The enemy's name is Fish Mooney.
"Fish Mooney"? She hasn't been spotted
for over six months.
She's either long gone or she's dead.
I wish I shared your simple belief.
She is a criminal.
She is a murderer.
And now God knows what kind of monster
Hugo Strange has turned her into.
I implore every citizen of Gotham,
if you love your family,
if you love your children,
find Fish Mooney.
Until then, no one is safe.
Hello, Jim.
Oswald.
I'm surprised you haven't found Mooney.
I hear you're quite the
bounty hunter these days.
You haven't made it worth my while.
Oh.
Tough guy now.
But he makes a point.
Ozzy.
Butch.
What a nice surprise.
Forgive me for not coming sooner.
The place looks marvelous!
- Wouldn't you say so, Butch?
- Yeah, place looks great.
I imagine you're here about your offer.
To let us shelter under your umbrella?
I only want what's best for you.
I appreciate the thought.
But... we're big girls.
We can handle ourselves.
Can't we?
Sure we can.
Hey, Butch.
Hey, h-h-how you doing?
You taking care of yourself?
Y-Yeah, yeah.
So, uh, so how you doing?
You already asked her that.
Listen.
You guys should take
him up on his offer.
Gotham's full of rough characters.
You look great by the way.
Wait over there.
Please.
Poor bunny.
Break-ups are hard.
I offered to kill you.
I thought it would raise his spirits.
It would be my pleasure seeing
as how you murdered my mother!
But he is nursing
some foolish hope that you
two will get back together.
Love.
You can take your offer
and stick it up...
We'll think about it, Ozzy.
Fine.
But that's not the only reason I'm here.
Spread the word.
I want Fish Mooney.
And I will give a million dollars...
to whoever can bring her to me.
Dead...
or alive.
Chopped into pieces.
I want her.
You okay, Butch?
World getting you down?
Yeah, I'm fine, kid.
And you're too young to be in here.
- Scram.
- Jeesh.
Just trying to be nice.
Just seeing her kills me, you know?
Get over it.
And that child just stole your wallet.
Hey, Barbara and that whip lady
are gonna get angry you
stealing from their customers.
Let them. I got other things going.
- Like what?
- Top secret.
Let's eat; I'm starving.
Hey, kid.
Take it. It's yours.
Keep feeding strays, one's
gonna follow you home.
Like you?
Well, that should be the last of it.
I'll put the kettle on.
There's nothing like a sweet cup of tea
to make home feel like home
after a long trip away.
Hey, Master Bruce?
You all right?
Were we right to leave, Alfred?
Stay away all this time?
Well, considering the
appalling sight of the topiary,
I should say absolutely bloody not.
Alfred, you know what I mean.
I know you know why we left.
We had to leave.
You're nervous about
tomorrow, aren't you?
- Yes.
- Well, you wouldn't
be human if you weren't.
So, why don't you go
through there, take a pew.
Pop your feet up,
and I'll see about
that lovely cup of tea.
All right?
Saving that for someone special?
Coffee, please.
"Search continues for new
Arkham Asylum director."
Right.
Good luck finding
anyone to take that job.
I'm Valerie Vale.
- Reporter for The Gazette.
- I know who you are.
And you're James Gordon.
Son of a respected Gotham D.A.
Former war hero. Former
white knight cop.
Now bounty hunter.
You know, someone should
do a story on you.
- Eh, not interested.
- Yeah, me neither, actually.
You were there that
night, at Indian Hill.
- I got nothing to say.
- What about the fact
that besides Hugo Strange
and his assistant,
no one else has been arrested?
Or that despite everything
pointing to Wayne Enterprises,
there seems to be zero investigation.
You're new to Gotham, aren't you?
Okay, this is where
you tell me things
work differently here?
I'm not from Gotham, but my dad's a cop.
My brothers are cops.
And things work the same everywhere.
I was going to say it's
hard to find a quiet bar
in the city.
I like coming here.
Please don't make me find another.
Now, do you think Cobblepot's right?
That Fish Mooney's
organizing the escapees?
Penguin is a liar and a murderer.
Hmm... but...
But based on the escapees,
and knowing Fish...
I hope not.
Well...
he's offering a million dollars
to whoever brings her in.
You're welcome.
It's a puzzle.
The trick is opening it.
The man at the store said
it's one of the most
difficult ever made.
People pass it down unsolved
for generations.
A mathematician once went mad trying...
Yes.
Well,
there you go.
It was a lovely thought.
And did you got the biscuits?
A-And the sweater?
I-I know how drafty these rooms are.
- Mr. Penguin.
- Oswald.
When I think of how I
treated you... Stop.
Why are you being so kind?
Talking to you these past months,
I don't know how I would've
gotten by otherwise.
With Fish out there
planning who knows what...
Me being surrounded by
morons and lunatics.
I know the feeling.
Why didn't she kill me
when she had the chance?
I was powerless.
She must have a larger goal.
I-I need to know what she is doing.
Do you?
When Alexander encountered
the Gordian knot,
a knot so complex no one had
ever been able to untangle it...
he just removed his
sword and cut it in two.
Details can be distracting.
Sometimes...
a simple solution is best.
See, no matter what she is planning,
just remember...
penguins...
eat...
fish.
You know why we're here.
- What are you doing here?
- Stop.
Stop...
So what are we after?
It's not like they keep cash around.
For now, survival. GUARD: Don't move!
Hands.
Of course.
Drop the gun.
Now knock yourself out.
That was awesome. How did you...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Whoa, Fish.
I'm fine.
Watch the door.
Yeah, that's the only
company that makes the drug.
Gray Pharma.
They actually have a
warehouse here in Gotham.
You think they could be a target?
Well, they're the only
pharmacy that carries the drug.
If somebody wants it, they'll
have to go to the source.
Let me find the address.
That's all right.
James Gordon.
Hands where I can see them.
So, what?
You're here to collect the
bounty Penguin has over my head?
What is it, a million dollars?
And to think I let that punk live.
Well, then,
I think you better cuff me.
Cuff yourself.
How many others you have with you?
They're all with me.
Every wretched soul
that Hugo Strange experimented on.
But tonight,
just him.
Did you hear them rats last night?
Scurrying around in the attic,
driving me bloody bonkers.
I'm gonna ask you,
what's the point of having a caretaker,
if they can't take care of nothing, aye?
You all right, Master B?
Hungry.
- I should've eaten.
- Excuse me, gentlemen.
I do this, there's no turning back.
No.
You say your piece.
We'll see about getting you a
proper breakfast, all right?
I'd like to thank the board
for giving me this time.
It will come as no surprise
I'd like to talk about Indian Hill.
I know preliminary
investigations have concluded
Hugo Strange acted alone.
I reject this conclusion.
While trapped in Indian
Hill, I was led to believe
an unnamed group had taken
control of my company,
and it was they who hired Hugo Strange.
I left Gotham
both for my own safety and so that
I might have the time to
discover hard evidence
of their existence.
A conspiracy theory?
That's why we're all here?
Excuse me, Master Bruce.
Pardon me, sir, might I
have your name, please?
- What?
- Your name... please, sir.
Crowley.
Mr. Crowley, did your parents
ever teach you any manners?
I don't have to listen to this.
Oh, but you do, sir!
That is precisely the
point that I am making.
I know how it sounds.
But I now have proof they exist.
And I can tell you that they're here.
In this room.
I want to talk face to face.
You have 24 hours to contact
me, or the information
that I've gathered will
be sent to every newspaper
and television station in Gotham.
Thank you for your time.
Pancakes?
Pancakes.
And how did the board react?
Then he leaves us no choice.
Bruce Wayne.
Do it quietly.
- You Barbara Kean?
- We're closed.
What?
You built this club on our territory.
We let you, 'cause we heard
Penguin had your back.
- And now we hear that ain't so.
- Oh.
Bad for you; good for us.
Get the hell out.
This place is ours now.
Do you understand?
You can't just come...
Don't hit me, okay? Please.
Hey. Hey.
You still paying for stuff
about the Indian Hill freaks?
Depends.
If it's good.
Is Fish Mooney good?
- Guess I'm finding a new bar.
- I heard you ran into
Fish Mooney yesterday.
- So?
- So...
are you still interested in finding her?
Every cop in the city's
looking for her now.
But I know where she's gonna be next.
- Why are you telling me?
- You see,
I need something from the cops.
They're not gonna tell me,
but Bullock still trusts you.
And you want me to lie to him.
A million dollars covers a lot of sins.
And obviously, I get to come along.
Aw. Don't tell me you have a conscience.
Yeah, all right.
Jimmy, hey. So...
after your run-in with Fish,
Barnes had us up all night,
rousting her old hideouts.
- Yeah. Did you find anything?
- Nada.
But I did get what you asked for.
Want to tell me what this is about?
It's a hunch. Probably nothing.
Well, if you got a hot lead
you don't want to share
so you can collect Penguin's money,
I got no problem with that.
Just don't get yourself
killed or me fired, okay?
I'll do my best. Hey,
get some rest, huh?
Hey.
When'd you get back?
A couple days ago.
I tried to find you before I left.
No worries.
You remember what I discovered
that night at Indian Hill?
That there was a secret group
that infiltrated my company.
I wasn't paying attention.
I needed time to research
them. I couldn't do it here.
Okay.
I have a plan, but these
people are powerful.
We need to assume they
know you and I are friends.
You need to be careful.
- Got it.
- I'm serious.
I can see that!
I'm sorry I was gone for so long.
Don't apologize.
Shoot, if I could fly to Italy
and eat pizza all day, I would, too.
- Switzerland.
- Italy's better.
- Selina...
- Bruce, seriously...
don't sweat it.
I got to go.
I'll see you around.
Good to see you, Selina.
- Hey, did you get it?
- Yeah.
She's under guard in a
building on Douglas and 80th.
There's one thing, though.
Hey. Hey!
What the hell are you doing?!
You're 100 yards from a police station.
I'll be back in an hour or two.
We had a deal.
If there's a story, I'll
make sure you get it.
Oh, you're a son of a bitch.
Also, you could scream,
but then you'd have
to tell the cops everything.
And you'd lose the story entirely.
Gordon.
Gordon!
Son of a bitch!
47... this is dispatch.
This is 47.
Report to Captain Barnes immediately.
Relief team will take
your place. Over and out.
You got it. We're out of here.
I knocked.
I didn't answer.
You alone?
All day, every day.
I wasn't expecting
Jim Gordon to stop by.
You aren't supposed to be here, are you?
How come you're not in jail?
I agreed to testify
against Professor Strange.
In case you're about to ask,
I don't know who really ran Indian Hill.
I don't care who ran Indian Hill.
Then why are you here?
Fish Mooney.
And why would I know
how to find Fish Mooney?
No reason you would.
But it's clear whatever
you and Strange did to her
is making her sick.
Her people are stealing drugs.
But I don't think they're working.
She's gonna come after you.
Or her goons will.
And they'll lead me to her.
And how will they find me?
Only the police are supposed to know.
My guess... she'll have someone
get the information for her.
Someone who wouldn't suspect being used.
Maybe a reporter.
She'll follow that person or whoever
she goes to for help.
In this case, a bounty hunter.
Right...
to you.
You led them to me on purpose.
You're using me as bait.
I don't like being played.
Plus she's worth a million dollars.
No! Gordon! Help!
Somebody help!
I don't know, which one of you
I want to bat over the
head with this cane more.
I get it.
Life disappointed you.
So what? Does that make you special?
I'm done with you.
You cross me again, I will
have you skinned alive
and your head put on a pike.
And you,
when I came back,
and saw the way you handled
things while I was away,
I swear, I had this feeling right here.
I thought I was having a heart attack.
But it was pride, Bullock.
In you.
The next time I have that feeling,
I'll know it was just gas.
You both better pray that we find her.
Get out of my sight.
I'd say that went well.
He was right though.
About me being Captain.
I did a good job. I even liked it.
Yeah. Hey, look, I'm sorry, Harvey.
I'll do my best to find Peabody.
Honestly, Jim,
for the time being, I think
it might be better if you just...
stayed away.
Hey. Hey!
- Ow.
- Just tell me, did you know?
Did I know what?
That Mooney was using
us to find Peabody.
You mean using you?
Yeah, it's her kind of play.
You should've told me.
Sure. Why don't you tell
me who your source was?
That's it?
You're not gonna try and find Mooney?
Barnes is on it. I've had a long day.
I'm gonna get a drink.
Gordon...
Nothing.
- Come on.
- I said no.
- Who are they?
- Just people.
They need me to do things for them.
Well, I can do stuff.
These are scary people, okay?
- It's for your own good.
- You just don't want to share.
Just stay here, all right?
Hello?
What do you want?
I want to talk to her.
I was following her.
She was kind to me.
But then she met him. That boy.
What happened to you?
- You know me?
- Uh, yeah. I know Bruce Wayne.
Who is he? Who is he?
What's wrong with you? Let go of me!
Bruce Wayne!
Bruce Wayne.
Who is he?
Really do not have time for this!
He started it.
It's a lie!
They cwub is in our territory
"Cwub?" What's a "cwub?"
Cwub.
What's a "cwub?" I mean,
can anyone understand him?
- Do you know what a "cwub" is?
- Cwub.
Enough.
We will work something out.
Now, this is his territory.
What are you willing to give him?
Boop.
That is not helpful.
Are you telling me you don't
see what's going on here?
He is behind this.
What are you talking about?
He sent this ding dong to squeeze us,
hoping it would send us back to you,
so that he could lord it over Tabby.
Ain't that right?
That's c... that's just... that's crazy.
She's crazy.
She was in Arkham. Hello?
"Hello?" So was I.
Is that true, Butch?
Unbelievable.
Fine. Run your club.
Just so we're clear,
the only reason you are alive
is Butch.
The moment he gives
the word, you're mine.
Hello again.
I know why you brought me here.
Your body is beginning to reject
the changes we made to your DNA.
You feel it every time you use...
your ability.
How do I fix it?
Stop using the power.
Every time you use it,
new cells are activated,
and your body rejects them.
Stop, and you will recover.
It's that simple.
It's just...
I like the new me.
I can't fix you.
I can't re-order your DNA...
There's... always a way.
Strange. He can.
He's the only one.
- Where is Strange?
- I don't know.
They've hidden him somewhere secret.
Him fixing me is just the beginning.
I want an army.
I want an army like me!
And he is going to give it to me.
- He can't.
- Oh, he will.
Or he will die.
You remember Marv.
He's one of yours.
Sort of a... fountain of youth
in reverse.
Good night, Ethel.
No!
We caught a spy.
Ivy?
Selina, tell this creep
to let go of me.
She's my friend.
- I don't like spies.
- She's not a spy.
Ivy, what are you doing here?
I followed you the other day,
so I knew where you went.
Bruce Wayne came looking for you,
but he was acting all weird...
Who else have you told about us?
- No one.
- I asked her.
- Selina...
- Ivy, shut up!
They're those monsters everyone's
talking about, aren't they?
You better tell your friend
to be careful who she calls a monster.
You better stay away from me.
All of you! I'll tell!
Marv?
No!
Leave her alone!
Stay away from me!
Ivy!
Watch out!
Help!
Ivy?
Right, once this alarm
is set, Master Bruce,
no coming downstairs till
the morning, is that clear?
Yes, but was a new alarm
system really necessary?
I don't know. Was it really necessary
offering a challenge to a shadowy cabal?
Yes, it was necessary, Master Bruce.
Alfred?
Alf...
Alfred!
Alfred, wake up.
- sync and corrections by madhatters -
- www.addic7ed.com -
www.tvsubtitles.net